David M. Stowe Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Resource Files: ABCFM/UCBWM Geographical / Topical Files, 1810-1990s; Series VI
  - Resource files: Topically arranged
    - Map distribution of Christian denominations in U.S., 1971 (Box 108, Folder 72)
    - Maps, 1955-1983, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 73)
    - Maps; Views of London in 1616 and 1890 (Box 179, Folder 35)
    - Maps of ACBFM missions, 1843 (Box 108, Folder 74)
    - Medical Fellowship, 1967-1970 (Box 109, Folder 75)
    - Medical Missions, 1915-1957 (Box 109, Folder 76)
    - Medical Missions, 1961-1990 (Box 109, Folder 77)
    - Merger of Congregational Christian Churches and Evangelical and Reformed Church, 1947-1957, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 1-8)
    - Minority groups in the UCC, 1977-1984 (Box 109, Folder 78)
    - Miscellaneous notes for Board history, 1986-1990 (Box 109, Folder 79)
    - Mission to America program, 1972-1976 (Box 109, Folder 80)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; Riggs family, 1948-1992 (Box 109, Folder 81)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, 1852-1959 (Box 109, Folder 82)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 109, Folder 83)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, 1972-1979 (Box 109, Folder 84)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, 1980-1989 (Box 110, Folder 85)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, 1990-1999 Feb 2 (Box 110, Folder 86)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, 1999 Feb 24 (Box 110, Folder 87)
    - Missionaries; Biographical information; miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 88)
    - Missionaries; Memorial tributes, 1960-1979 (Box 110, Folder 89)
    - Missionaries who served in China, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 90)
    - Missionary candidate papers; sample, 1950-1963 (Box 110, Folder 91)
    - Missionary education, 1894-1962, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 92)
    - Missionary education; plays, 1956, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 93)
    - Missionary formation / role, 1812-1965 (Box 111, Folder 94)
    - Missionary formation / role, 1967-1984 (Box 111, Folder 95)
    - Missionary formation /role, 1985-1999, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 96)
    - Missionary Handbook ABCFM, 1953 (Box 111, Folder 97)
    - Missionary Herald newsletter, 1959-1960 (Box 111, Folder 98)
    - Missionary marriage, 1817? 1979, 1991, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 99)
    - Missionary "martyrs", 1862,1981-1990 (Box 111, Folder 100)
    - Missionary motivation, 1947-1952 (Box 111, Folder 101)
    - Missionary motivation, 1957-1961, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 102)
    - Missionaries; statistics, 1927, 1970 (Box 112, Folder 103)
    - Missions in seminaries, 1980 (Box 112, Folder 104)
    - Mook, Telfer, 1965,1991 (Box 112, Folder 105)
    - Moravian Church, 1952,1990 (Box 112, Folder 106)
    - Morning Star sailing ships, 1856-1955 (Box 112, Folder 107)
    - Morning Star sailing ships, 1957-1958 (Box 112, Folder 108)
    - Morning Star sailing ships, 1959-1999 (Box 112, Folder 109)
    - Morning Star sailing ships, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 110)
    - National Christian leaders; Africa incl. Sithole, Tutu, 1955-1997, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 111)
    - National Christian leaders; India incl. Hivale, 1955-1973 (Box 112, Folder 112)
    - National Christian leaders; Japan incl. Nessima, 1859-1976, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 113)
    - National Christian leaders; miscellaneous, 1854-1971, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 114)
    - National Christian leaders; Photographs, 1949 (Box 179, Folder 36)
    - Oberlin College; Memorial arch controversy, 1991 (Box 113, Folder 115)
    - Olivet College controversy, 1948-1998 (Box 113, Folder 116)
    - Origins and history of ABCFM, 1885-1910, 1936, 1957-1960 (Box 113, Folder 117)
    - Origins and history of ABCFM, 1976-1992 (Box 113, Folder 118)
    - Origins and history of ABCFM (Box 113, Folder 119)
    - Origins and history of ABCFM; The Ely Volume, 1881 (Box 113, Folder 120)
    - Origins and history of ABCFM; Officers, 1810, n.d. (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Origins and history of ABCFM; old newspaper clippings, 1857, 1895, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 121)
    - Origins and history of the Board; chronology, 1957,1983-1993, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 122)
    - Origins and history of the Board; 75th and 100th anniversaries, 1910, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 123)
    - Origins and history of the Board; 150th anniversary, 1959-1970 (Box 114, Folder 124)
    - Origins and history of the Board; 150th anniversary, 1981-1985 (Box 114, Folder 125)
    - Origins and history of the Board; 150th anniversary (Box 114, Folder 126)
    - Origins and history of the Board; Haystack Prayer meeting, 1806 - 1998 (Box 114, Folder 127)
    - Origins and history of the Board; Haystack 175th anniversary, 1819-1981 (Box 114, Folder 128)
    - Origins and history of the Board; Haystack 175th anniversary, 1984-1985 (Box 114, Folder 129)
    - Origins and history of the Board; miscellaneous, 1955-1978 (Box 114, Folder 130)
    - Origins and history of the Board; miscellaneous, 1981-1990, n. d. (Box 114, Folder 131)
    - Origins and history of the Board; artifacts and memorabilia, 1822,1974-1990, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 132)
    - Origins and history of the Board; Pembroke Conference, 1957 (Box 115, Folder 133)
    - Pacific Asian American Ministries (PAAM), 1980 (Box 179, Folder 37)
    - Partnership with overseas churches, 1962,1990, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 134)
    - Planning, 1944-1966 (Box 115, Folder 135)
    - Planning, 1967-1975 (Box 115, Folder 136)
    - Planning, 1976-1981 (Box 115, Folder 137)
    - Planning, 1982-1986, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 138)
    - Planning; Finance, 1962-1980, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 139)
    - Planning; Personnel, 1978-1980, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 140)
    - Planning; Scenarios, 1977 (Box 116, Folder 141)
    - Planning; Scenarios, 1981 (Box 116, Folder 142)
    - Presbyterian mission and ABCFM, 1952 (Box 116, Folder 143)
    - Program opportunities fund, 1972-1984 (Box 116, Folder 144)
    - Public policy of Board; resolutions, 1975-1983 (Box 116, Folder 145)
    - Publicity/ appeals, 1895-1896, 1925-1956 (Box 116, Folder 146)
    - Publicity / appeals, 1964-1984, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 147)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals, 1856,1939-1950 (Box 116, Folder 148)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals, 1952-1962 (Box 116, Folder 149)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals, 1954-1972 (Box 117, Folder 150)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals, 1973-1979 (Box 117, Folder 151)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals, 1980-1984,n.d. (Box 117, Folder 152)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals; "Reply to the Committee on Structure", 1966 (Box 117, Folder 153)
    - Purpose/ policy/ goals; Role of mission Board, 1947-1989, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 154)
    - Racism and Board, 1969-1983,n.d. (Box 117, Folder 155)
    - Relationship of Board to United Church of Christ, 1961-1995 (Box 117, Folder 156)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1905, 1940-1984 (Box 117, Folder 157)
    - Schwenkfelder Church, 1949-1989,n.d. (Box 117, Folder 158)
    - Science and missions (Box 117, Folder 159)
    - Seminars on Salvation Today and Contemporary Experience, 1972 (Box 118, Folder 160)
    - Service and missions, 1943-1986 (Box 118, Folder 161)
    - Service and missions (Box 118, Folder 162)
    - Sex ethics and sexuality policy, 1969-1980,n.d. (Box 118, Folder 163)
    - Slavery, 1997-1998 (Box 179, Folder 38)
    - Social and political concerns, 1953-1983 (Box 118, Folder 164)
    - Southern Convention of Congregational Christian Churches, 1950 (Box 118, Folder 165)
    - Staff; Board executives, 1961, 1990, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 166)
    - Staff; Anderson, Rufus, 1954-1992 (Box 118, Folder 167)
    - Staff; Seabury, Ruth Isabel, 1955-1956 (Box 119, Folder 168)
    - Staff; Equal Employment Opportunity, 1975-1976 (Box 119, Folder 169)
    - Staff; Policies, 1940-1971 (Box 119, Folder 170)
    - Staff; Policies, 1972-1975 (Box 119, Folder 171)
    - Staff; Policies, 1976-1980,n.d. (Box 119, Folder 172)
    - Staff; Recruiting, 1975-1979 (Box 119, Folder 173)
    - Staff; Statements of doctrinal belief, samples, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 174)
    - Staff; "UCBWM Dames" events, 1970-1980 (Box 119, Folder 175)
    - Stationery samples, 1984, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 176)
    - Stewardship, 1958, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 177)
    - Stewardship; Paper by Charles A. Maxfield; "Missions, Money and Motivation: Development of a Theology of Stewardship of the ABCFM", 1992 (Box 119, Folder 178)
    - Stowe Fund, 1984-1985 (Box 120, Folder 179)
    - Strategy, 1961, 1977 (Box 120, Folder 180)
    - Theology of mission of Board, 1950-1978 (Box 120, Folder 181)
    - Theology of mission of Board, 1979-1986, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 182)
    - Theology of missions, 1967-1976 (Box 120, Folder 183)
    - Theology of missions, 1977-1983, n.d.. (Box 120, Folder 184)
    - "Tidbits", 1847-1985 (Box 120, Folder 185)
    - Tributes to Board, including from John K. Fairbank, 1963, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 186)
    - Trip reports by Board staff, 1985-1992 (Box 120, Folder 187)
    - Use of U.S. government, 1963-1978 (Box 120, Folder 188)
    - Walker Missionary Home, 1976, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 189)
    - Woman's Board of Missions, 1926-1985, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 190)
    - Woman's Board of Missions of the Interior, 1914, n.d. (Box 179, Folder 39)
    - Women Corporate members, 1972 (Box 121, Folder 191)
    - Women in relation to the Board, 1882-1995 (Box 121, Folder 192)
    - Women in relation to the Board, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 193)
    - Women missionaries, 1953-1990 (Box 121, Folder 194)
    - World Issues Task Force, 1971 (Box 121, Folder 195)
- Resource Files: "DMS Working Files", 1950s-1990s; Series VII
  This series represents the extensive alphabetical filing system kept by Stowe to organize collected materials and notes on a variety of topics and issues. It gives a good sense of the wide range of his interests and involvements.
  - ﻿Aging; AIDS; Almanac (Box 122, Folder 1-3)
  - ﻿America (Box 122, Folder 4-9)
  - ﻿American Missionary Association; ﻿American Values; Amistad; Amnesty International; Anti-Christian Bias; ﻿Art; Beauty; Birds (Box 122, Folder 10-17)
  - Asia Theology; Post colonial (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - ﻿Books -- Bibliography (Box 123, Folder 18-20)
  - ﻿Black Manifesto (Box 123, Folder 21-24)
  - ﻿Bulletin of the Congregational Library; Carleton College; ﻿Central Atlantic Conference; Charismatic; Children; China (Box 123, Folder 25-30)
  - China: Study Packet, Friendship Press; Summary and Index of China News in The New York Times and Christian Science Monitor by Archie R. Crouch; Misc. reports and articles including by Archie Crouch, Donald MacInnis, Creighton Lacy; maps (Box 200, Folder 1-8)
  - China: Maps of Beijing, Chongqing; Historical charts (Box 200, Folder 9-10)
  - ﻿Christian Peacemaker Teams (CPT) (Box 123, Folder 31-34)
  - ﻿Christmas; ﻿Church Architecture; Church Growth; Church and State; Church World Service (Box 124, Folder 35-40)
  - Church and Communism (Box 199, Folder 2-4)
  - ﻿CIA and DOM (Division of Overseas Ministries); Clinton, President Bill; Columbus, Christopher; ﻿Communication; Communism; Computers; Congregational Christian Historical Society (CCHS) (Box 124, Folder 41-48)
  - ﻿Congregational Christian Historical Society (CCHS); ﻿Consultation on Church Union (COCU) (Box 125, Folder 49-51, 52)
  - ﻿Conversion; Cosmos; Cultures; Death Penalty; Democracy; ﻿Development; Doshisha; Drummond, Richard; Ecology (Box 125, Folder 53-65)
  - Economy/ poverty; Ecumenism; Eisley, Loren (Scientist); ﻿Elyn MacInnis; Equality; Ethics, Universal; Europe (Box 126, Folder 66-72)
  - ﻿Evangelicals; Evangelism; Evolution; Family and Marriage (Box 126, Folder 74-79,80,81)
  - ﻿Freedom; Fundamentalists Anonymous; Funerals; Futurology (Box 127, Folder 82-85)
  - ﻿Hambrick-Stowe, Charles; ﻿Harvard Divinity School; ﻿Hawaii; Health Care; ﻿Henderson, Lawrence; Historical Society, UCC; Holst, Dr. Wayne (regarding Native Americans); Homosexuality; Hong Kong; Honolulu; Human Rights (Box 127, Folder 86-98)
  - ﻿Humor (Box 127, Folder 99-100, Box 128, Folder 101-103)
  - ﻿Hutchison, Frank; Hymns; ﻿Ideas; ﻿Imperialism; ﻿Indians (Native Americans); ﻿Inspirations; Iraq; ﻿Japan, Jews (Box 128, Folder 104-113)
  - ﻿Jews (Box 129, Folder 114-123)
  - ﻿Justice; ﻿Koinonia Community; ﻿Kosovo; ﻿Latin America; Lavely, John H. (Box 129, Folder 124-128)
  - ﻿Lay Ministry; ﻿Liberation Theology﻿; MacInnis, Donald; Marriage; Marxism; Maryknoll; Middle East Panel Report (Box 130, Folder 129)
  - Lux Mundi (Box 201, Folder 11)
  - ﻿Mission: Board, Challenges, Hymns, Industry, Money, Problems, Statistics, Strategy, Theology; Missionary (Box 130, Folder 137-147)
  - ﻿Missionary Recruitment, Six-Continent Exchange; Missions, Evangelical Theology of; Modernity; Modernity; Moratorium, Mormons (Box 131, Folder 148-157)
  - ﻿National Council of Churches; Nature; Nazarene, Church of the; New Jersey Association, Central Atlantic Conference (Box 131, Folder 158-161)
  - ﻿New Jersey Association, Pre-Ordination Commission; New Yorker cartoons; Nixon, Richard; Nuclear Issues; One World Culture; Orthodoxy; Orwell, George (Box 132, Folder 162-169)
  - ﻿Pacific School of Religion (PSR); Peace; ﻿Pentecostal; Persecuted Christians; Persian Gulf; Phi Beta Kappa; Poetry (Box 132, Folder 170-176)
  - ﻿Political Theology; ﻿Politics (Clinton Memorabilia); Population Control; Pragmatism; ﻿Prayer (Box 132, Folder 177-182)
  - ﻿Pre-Ordination Papers and Procedures; Progress; Promise Keepers; Race in America (Box 133, Folder 183-188)
  - ﻿Rahbar, David; Redemption; ﻿Religious Liberty (in Nepal); Religious Right; Reuling, John A. Memorial; Revolution (Box 133, Folder 189-196)
  - ﻿Rexroth, Kenneth; ﻿Rights; Roman Catholic; Roosevelt; Science (Box 133, Folder 197-202)
  - ﻿Science; Sex; Simpson, O.J.; ﻿Spirituality; ﻿Souvenirs, United Church Board for World Ministries; ﻿Technology; Tenafly, NJ (Box 134, Folder 203-212)
  - ﻿Theology (Theodicy and Process Theology); United Nations; ﻿Values; Van Dusen, Henry (Box 134, Folder 213-217)
  - ﻿Vietnam (National Council of the Churches of Christ, Mennonite Central Committee, Associated Church Press, other documents); Violence (in Latin America, South Africa, etc.); Welfare; World Conference on Religion and Peace (WCRP - United Church of Christ); World Council of Churches (Box 135, Folder 218-225)
  - ﻿Women; Wood, Agnes (South African Missionary -- stories, articles, letters); World Christian Encyclopedia; Worship History; Young, Andrew (Box 135, Folder 226-233)
  - Women; Worship (Box 201, Folder 12-13)
- DMS Activities: Church and Ecumenical, 1954-1999; Series VIII
  This series documents Stowe's involvement with church and ecumenical organizations. Official correspondence and documents related to the ABCFM/UCBWM would be in the UCBWM archives in Cleveland. The "Meetings and Conferences" sub-series documents Stowe's participation in many of the most important mission-related and ecumenical gatherings of the second half of the 20th century.
  - ABCFM/UCBWM administration and archives
    - Correspondence, reports, etc., 1956, 1969-1985, n.d. (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - CIA and Missionaries; Correspondence, reports, clippings, 1975-1976, 1980 (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - Transition memos, 1985 Jan (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - Special Assignment in Beirut
    - Writings, reports, notes, 1954-1969, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - Financial tax, personal records, 1955-1962, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 181, Folder 6-7)
    - Near East School of Theology: Correspondence, reports, 1962- 1964, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 8-9)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ USA DOM
    - China Program
      - Reports, etc., 1964-1970 (Box 182, Folder 10-13)
    - Executive Committee
      - Meeting minutes, 1966-1969 (Box 183, Folder 14-16)
    - Other committees, programs
      - UCBWM Committee minutes, 1967 (Box 183, Folder 17)
      - Reports, pamphlets, etc., 1962-1968 (Box 184, Folder 18)
      - EACC Consultation; Reports, clippings, etc., 1965 Dec (Box 184, Folder 19)
      - Planning, reports, pamphlets, etc., 1966-1982 (Box 184, Folder 20)
      - Reports, pamphlets, etc., 1969-1985 (Box 184, Folder 21)
      - Minutes of DOM staff meetings (Box 184, Folder 22)
  - World Council of Churches
    - Missions, 1958-1961 (Box 185, Folder 23)
    - CWME Bangkok; Reports, etc., 1963-1973 (Box 185, Folder 24)
    - Events/ Ecumenical; Reports, 1963, 1974, 1980 (Box 185, Folder 25)
    - Activities; Minutes, reports, etc., 1964-1983 (Box 185, Folder 26)
    - Uppsala and mission; Pamphlets, notes, clippings, 1968 (Box 185, Folder 27)
    - Fourth Assembly programs, reports, brochures, 1968 (Box 186, Folder 28)
    - Fourth Assembly newspaper clippings; Uppsala News, 1968 (Box 186, Folder 29)
    - Uppsala youth, 1968 (Box 186, Folder 30)
    - Nairobi; Travel materials, etc., 1975 (Box 186, Folder 31)
    - Glion Consultation, 1978-1979 (Box 187, Folder 32)
    - Reports, correspondence, etc., 1980, 1982, n.d. (Box 187, Folder 33)
  - Meetings and conferences
    Arrangement
    Chronological file of trips and meetings undertaken in a variety of positions.
    - World trip, 1960-1968 (Box 161, Folder 336)
    - Beirut; Jerusalem, 1961-1963 (Box 161, Folder 337-339)
    - New Delhi, 1961 (Box 161, Folder 340-343)
    - Hawaii, 1962 (Box 162, Folder 344)
    - East Asia Christian Conference, 1962 (Box 162, Folder 345)
    - Kampala, Africa: All Africa Church Conference (AACC); Africa: General, 1963 (Box 162, Folder 346-347)
    - Lebanon, 1963 (Box 162, Folder 348)
    - Singapore: East Asia Christian Conference (EACC), 1963-1964 (Box 162, Folder 349-350)
    - Latin America, 1966 (Box 162, Folder 351)
    - Africa; Nairobi, Kenya: World Council of Churches (WCC), 1967 (Box 162, Folder 352-353)
    - Latin America; Mexico, 1968 (Box 163, Folder 354-355)
    - Uppsala, Sweden: World Council of Churches (WCC), 1968 (Box 163, Folder 356-360)
    - Hawaii, 1970 (Box 163, Folder 361)
    - Latin America, 1970-1971 (Box 164, Folder 362)
    - Nairobi, South Africa, 1970 (Box 164, Folder 363-366)
    - Portugal, 1970 (Box 164, Folder 367)
    - Latin America, 1971 (Box 164, Folder 368)
    - Japan, 1971-1972 (Box 164, Folder 369)
    - Turkey, 1971-1972 (Box 165, Folder 370)
    - Asia; Philippines; Hong Kong, 1972 (Box 165, Folder 371-373)
    - Asia; India; Japan, 1974 (Box 165, Folder 374-376)
    - Near East; New Delhi; Switzerland, 1974 (Box 166, Folder 378-380)
    - Nairobi; Portugal; Indonesia; Japan, 1975-1976 (Box 166, Folder 381-386)
    - Philippines' Asia (UCC trip); Costa Rica; India; Micronesia, 1975-1976 (Box 167, Folder 387-392)
    - Micronesia; Latin America; Europe; Korea; Taiwan, 1976-1978 (Box 168, Folder 393-403)
    - Nepal; Australia; Germany; Hawaii; Central America; India, 1979-1981 (Box 169, Folder 404-409)
    - Sri Lanka: Fourth International Consultation of United and Uniting Churches, 1981-1982 (Box 170, Folder 410-413)
    - Silver Bay, NY: Eastern Ecumenical Conference on the Christian World Mission; Conference materials, correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 172, Folder 437)
    - Lebanon; India; Nepal, 1982-1983 (Box 170, Folder 414-417)
    - Czechosolvakia; Korea; Germany; Turkey; Zimbabwe, 1983-1984 (Box 171, Folder 418-427)
    - Africa; Zambia; Amsterdam; Israel; Kenya (World Conference on Religion and Peace); Turkey, 1984 (Box 172, Folder 428-436)
  - ﻿American Society of Missiology Eastern Fellowship
    - ﻿Financial Records; Ledger Book; Membership and Meetings, ﻿1984-1990 (Box 136, Folder 1-15)
    - ﻿Financial Records; Membership and Meetings, ﻿1991-1995 (Box 137, Folder 16-28)
    - ﻿Financial Records; Membership and Meetings, ﻿1996-1999, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 29-40)
  - ﻿China Tours
    - ﻿﻿Tour information: itineraries, participant lists, tour reports; Group briefing materials (pronunciation guides, etc.); Keepsakes: tourist brochures, Chinese money and stamps; Newspaper clippings (Chinese and American); telegram to Virginia Stowe, ﻿1979 (Box 139, Folder 41-44)
    - ﻿﻿"China Study Outline for the United Church of Christ Participants in the 1981 China Tour"; Group briefing materials, itineraries, participant lists; Tour reports; Keepsakes: tourist brochures, Chinese money and stamps; Newspaper clippings (Box 139, Folder 45-49)
    - ﻿Group briefing materials; ﻿Itineraries, participant lists; ﻿Tour reports; Keepsakes: tourist brochures, Chinese money and stamps; Newspaper clippings; Tour-related correspondence, ﻿1985 (Box 139, Folder 50-52, Box 140, Folder 53-55)
    - ﻿Itineraries and participant lists; Tour reports, newsclippings; Tour-related correspondence; ﻿Group briefing materials, itineraries, participant lists, ﻿1986-1987 (Box 140, Folder 56-59)
    - ﻿﻿Itineraries and participant lists; Tour reports, tour correspondence; Group briefing materials; Keepsakes and brochures, ﻿1987-1988 (Box 141, Folder 60-65)
    - ﻿Group briefing, itinerary (cancelled);Correspondence; Tour brochure; newspaper clippings, tour-related correspondence, undated brochures, ﻿1989, 1999, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 66-69)
- DMS Career Activities: Teaching and Research, 1949-1990s; Series IX
  In addition to his executive administration positions with organizations, Stowe also taught and engaged in research projects throughout his career. This series documents courses he taught and his strong interest in Process Theology and Interreligious Dialogue. The final sub-series contains valuable biographical documentation about ABCFM missionaries to 1957, compiled for a proposed project to update the "Vinton" books.
  - Courses Taught
    - Yenching University, 1949-1950
      - English Composition (Box 193, Folder 15-16)
      - Western Philosophy (Box 194, Folder 17)
    - Carleton College, 1953-1956
      - History of Christian World Missions (Box 191, Folder 1)
      - Christian Theology (Box 191, Folder 2)
      - Classical Christian Thought (Box 191, Folder 3)
      - Comparative Religions (Box 191, Folder 4)
      - Contemporary Christian Thought (Box 191, Folder 5)
      - New Testament (Box 191, Folder 6)
      - Old Testament (Box 191, Folder 7)
      - Religions of Mankind (Box 191, Folder 8)
    - Near East School of Theology, 1962-1963
      - Christian Ethics (Box 192, Folder 9-11)
      - Faith of the Christian Church (Box 192, Folder 12)
      - History of Christian Thought (Box 192, Folder 13)
    - Andover- Newton Theological Seminary (ANTS), 1950s-1960s, 1980s-1990s
      - China
        - Art; A-V resources; ANS news service; Bibliography; Book notes; Boxers (Box 142, Folder 70-76)
        - Chao; Christianity in China; China articles; China in 2000; China Church Quarterly; China Connection; China Focus; China Insight (Box 142, Folder 77-85)
        - China News Update; China policy document; China statistics; "China Talk": United Methodist Church newsletter; China Watching; Church in China; Church and society; Church and state; Chronologies; Communists; Culture-general (Box 143, Folder 86-96)
        - Economy; Ecumenical and missionary relations; Elyn letters; Environmental; Florida (Box 143, Folder 97-101)
        - Folk religions; Global Chinese ministries; Government/ politics; Growth of China church; Health/ medicine; Hong Kong; Human rights; Imperialism; Indexes; Indigenization; International bulletin; International relations (Box 144, Folder 102-113)
        - Jesus family/ true Jesus/ little flock; Language; Letters; Maoism; Minorities; Miscellaneous; Missionary history (Box 144, Folder 114-123)
        - Missions; Music; Nestorians; Newsletters; Peking (letters 1951-1955); Philosophy: Chinese; Protestant churches; Publications; Religion (Box 145, Folder 124-134)
        - Religion: Catholics; Religion and state; Sects; Spotlight on China; Statistics; Taiping; Talks; Tentmakers; Theological education; Tiananmen rights (Box 146, Folder 135-145)